

Submitted to Amentum for ARPA-H STATS

NAME	JOB TITLE	PWS Tasks
Jason Bulger	DOC - Advanced Marketing Specialist	7.1.7; 7.8.1-7.8.3

Job Responsibility	Qualifying Skills
Marketing Strategy Development: Develop and implement marketing strategies and campaigns to enhance engagement with ARPA-H's brand, content, events, funding opportunities, and employment needs.	 Managed marketing and branding strategies for urgent and specialty care centers, ambulatory services, and outpatient imaging networks at MedStar Health. Led digital content development for campaigns, from storyboarding to distribution. Designed bilingual marketing campaigns to bridge gaps with underserved populations in Washington, DC.
Stakeholder Collaboration: Build and nurture collaborative relationships with internal teams, external stakeholders, and partners to support marketing goals.	 Served as a subject matter expert and liaison between marketing leadership and operational teams. Collaborated with digital marketing teams and external vendors to reduce acquisition costs by \$30K for strategic expansion. Authored communications for global audiences at the American Association of Blood Banks (AABB), ensuring consistent messaging.
Campaign Performance & Optimization: Monitor and evaluate marketing campaign performance, providing reports and recommendations for continuous improvement.	 Tracked profitability, marketing efforts, and budget allocations at AABB to improve engagement and revenue growth. Managed a \$1.2MM annual budget at MedStar Health, overseeing reconciliations and strategic investments. Developed KPIs and reporting processes for branding, consumer engagement, and retention strategies.

Education

M.B.A., Business Administration, University of Maryland Global Campus

May 2022

B.S., Marketing, The University of Tulsa

Experience

MedStar Health, Columbia, MD

2013 - Present

Manager, Marketing and Communications - Ambulatory Services

- · Manage all marketing and branding strategies for urgent and specialty care center locations, ambulatory surgery centers, outpatient imaging network, and radiation oncology services.
- · Serve as the subject matter expert to operational teams and leadership for all campaigns for execution.
- · Analyze needs, identify solutions, execute pre-projects, develop processes, implement solutions, and manage budgets and deadlines.
- · Ensure brand consistency and quality with expertise in development, technology, and integration.
- · Secure \$1.2MM annual budget plan; Partner with Marketing leadership to successfully reconcile monthly expenditures.



- · Increase consumer network with new facility marketing campaign to accelerate revenue at both urgent and specialty care center locations.
- · Collaborate with management and teams to ensure brand continuity.
- · Contribute knowledge and experience as a mentor to junior associates in the company's formal program.
- · Develop digital media content from storyboarding to distribution.

Manager, System Marketing and Communications

2013 - 2015

- · Delivered and updated all advertisement content for multiple communication channels that included digital platforms, tv, print, radio, direct mail, and mobile applications.
- · Facilitated all brand campaign efforts for both project and product launches.
- · Researched, collaborated, and coordinated with digital marketing teams and external resources to deliver topnotch marketing initiatives.
- Oversaw a \$180K budget for mystery shopping campaign and instituted cost-effective branding measures for long-term business success.

American Association of Blood Banks, Bethesda, MD Marketing Manager

2008 - 2013

- · Planned, implemented, and executed all international marketing campaigns, designs, augmented member recruitment, consumer retention plans, and promotional activities to drive revenue and long-term engagement.
- · Monitored marketing plans, budgets, vendor relations, branding enhancements, and strategically made recommendations to leadership.
- Authored all communications for distribution to global member and non-member audiences. Ongoingly conducted industry research, honed best practices, and identified competitive and product positioning tactics.
- Accelerated the performance of all marketing and promotional activities that included electronic and print media for accreditation, membership, consulting, regulatory affairs, global development, biovigilance, professional development departments, and national blood exchange efforts.
- · Tracked profitability, marketing efforts, budgetary allocations, and instituted modifications to boost engagement and growth.

Marketing Specialist, BaySaver Technologies, Inc.,	2007-2008
Marketing Communications and Business Development, MedStar Health/Nascott Orthotics and Prosthetics	2003-2007
Business Analyst I, Williams Communications Group,	2001-2002
Marketing Intern, HILTI, Inc.,	1999-2000
Military Experience, United States Navy Hospital Corpsman	1992– 1996